TRIPTI WANI

Full Stack Web Developer

Telephone +61 481 254 765 Email tripti.895@gmail.com Address Sydney, Australia Website triptiwani.github.io

PROFILE

I am a full stack web developer with a strong interest in projects that require both conceptual and analytical thinking. I love to solve problems with code while applying industry best practices in a collaborative environment. Fullycommitted to designing and developing innovative web-based materials that users will love. Focused and self-motivated professional, with 7 years experience in Information Technology. Always eager to learn more tricks from anyone - regardless of the industry they're working in.

Technical Skills

HTML CSS

Javascript Ajax

jQuery Backbone.js

Ruby Three.js

Ruby on Rails Underscore.js

Bootstrap SQL/Postgres

Git/Heroku TDD - Rspec,

UNIX Scripting Cucumber

Stencyl RESTful APIs

References

Joel Turnbull, Instructor,GA Bala R., RXP Services Limited

Contact details are available on request

EXPERIENCE

CODE CAMP Teaching Assistant

Assisted the Head Teacher, troubleshooted the issues faced by kids. Helped kids develop logic, computational thinking, user experience, creativity by problem solving while building apps and games.

Tech Stack Stency

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

June 2016 - Aug 2016

Spring Holidays 2016

General Assembly is a pioneer in education and career transformation, specialising in today's most in-demand skills.

TALK2ME

User friendly web-based chat application covering photos, gifs and location with a Mobile-first approach.

Tech HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby,Rails 5, Puma/Redis,Cloudinary/ **Stack** Bootstrap, Gifshot.is, GoogleMaps.js,jQueryAutoComplete.js

PALATE

A mobile-first app for creating, bookmarking and sharing recipes from any existing recipe websites via chrome extension.

Tech HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,RUBY /RAILS 4.2.6, Cloudinary/

Stack Bootstrap, Nokogiri, bcrypt, httparty, ratyrate, Chorme Dev tool, Padilicious.js

INVENTORY MANAGEMENT

This is an e-commerce website to procure, track and deal in Mobile handsets and accessories for wholesalers and retailers across multiple locations with the built-in payment feature.

Tech HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby /Rails 4.2.6, Cloudinary/Sendgrid, Stripe.js, **Stack** money-rails Twitter/Facebook/bcrypt

INFOSYS LIMITED

July 2008 - Sep 2015

Infosys Limited is an Indian multinational corporation that provides business consulting, information technology and outsourcing services.

Software Engineer/Technology Lead

Worked on multiple projects across domains and technologies. My commitment and dedication helped me move up to a Lead position really quickly.

- Worked on the ETL Framework migration for a prestigious AUS Bank
- Interactions with the business analysts for analysis and design, understanding the technical requirements to be applied during development
- Provide technical mentoring, perform reviews and contribute to functional and technical documents
- Planning and tracking 24*7 production support cycle, analyse and suggest/implement work-around and perform Root Cause Analysis and fixes to avoid re-occurence
- Handling Configuration Management and Control
- Creation of source code for conversion/collection programs

HIGHLIGHT

SIGNMEUP - SheHacks2016 organised by GirlGeekSydney

Building a sign language translator app for people with hearing loss and received Third place.

http://site-55311-9163-8820.strikingly.com/

EDUCATION

2016 - 2016 Web Development Immersive General Assembly, Sydney

2011 - 2013 MBA in Human Resource Symbiosis, India

2004 - 2008 M.Sc. (Hons.) Chemistry – Integrated Course

BITS Pilani, India